Owen Campbell

Email Website Location

Mobile Phone +44 (0)7799 111652 owen.campbell@tanti.org.uk owencampbell.me.uk Helsby, Cheshire UK

Profile

I first learned to program as a child of the 1980s, on the ZX81 and BBC Micro, and have never stopped. I've programmed in Fortran, Visual Basic, Java, TSQL, PL/SQL, C#, Ruby and Python. I've created database APIs in SQL Server and Oracle, web applications with Django, Ruby on Rails and AngularJS, GUI applications with .NET and a host of other interfaces and apps.

In my early career with ICI, I was the technical manager for several EC funded collaborative research projects. Since forming my own consultancy, I have concentrated on bringing robust and agile technical practices to the world of finance and accounting - improving the world by ridding it of one spreadsheet at a time!

In my spare time, I'm a core team member of the Axelrod-Python project (https://github.com/Axelrod-Python/Axelrod), an open source game theory research project and I'm a co-author of a paper describing the project. (http://dx.doi.org/10.5334/jors.125).

I'm an active member of the Python UK community and regularly speak at relevant conferences (e.g. http://2016.pyconuk.org/talks/ancient-greek-philosophy-medieval-mental-models-and-21st-century-technology/).

Employment History

2001 – Current	Owner and Director, Empiria Ltd In March 2001, along with two colleagues, I left Eutech to form my own consulting company, Empiria Ltd.
1998 – 2001	Business System Manager, Eutech Ltd In 1998, ICI decided to sell Eutech and I became the lead engineer on a project to implement an integrated financials, logistics, project accounting and HR system. I then became the manager of that system and led its maintenance, development and support.
1994 – 1998	Technology Project Manager, Eutech Ltd Eutech was a wholly owned subsidiary of ICI PLC which provided engineering consultancy services to the process industries. I joined at its inception in a role providing technical leadership of collaborative R&D projects between ICI PLC and other EU organisations. I particularly specialised in the innovative design and use of relational databases.
1990 – 1994	Project Engineer, ICI PLC I joined ICI as a graduate engineer and worked on a variety of engineering projects

Education and Qualifications

for ICI businesses in the UK.

1995	CEng MIET Chartered Engineer, Member of the Institution of Engineering Technology
	(www.theiet.org (Formerly the Institution of Electrical Engineering)
1990	BEng (Hons) Engineering Science and Technology (University of Loughborough)

Interests and Hobbies

I am a voluntary senior manager for the UK Scout Association (District Commissioner for the Mersey Weaver Scout District: www.merseyweaverscouts.org.uk).

The role involves overall responsibility for the delivery of Scouting to the District's 1250 young people and line management of its 250 adult volunteers.